# Rakesh Chaudhary

# Senior Analyst

- arcsle09plus@gmail.com
- **\** 9998006038/7016731487
- Detailed CV

#### Profile

An accomplished Technology & Research Professional and Certified Scrum Master(SAFE) having 6 years of experience in all phases of agile software development lifecycle. Passionate about Analytics Engineering Technologies and delivery of effective solutions through creative problem-solving.

#### Education

Master of Science - Financial **Mathematics**, Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda 🗷 Jun 2016 - Jun 2018

## Certification

- Certified SAFe® 6 Scrum Master □
- Google Cloud Skills ☑
- Databricks Lakehouse Fundamentals 🛮
- HackerRank ☑

# Professional Experience

### Manager - TB Cash Analytics,

Standard Chartered Bank 🛭

May 2024 - present | Bangalore, India

- Contributing as Analytics Engineer to build Cash Data Lake using Bank's various OLTP systems.
- Leading the Reporting Automations Initiatives aiming to generate Bank's Cash Revenue Opportunities.

# **Senior Analyst**, NielsenIQ ☑

Nov 2018 - May 2024 | Remote

- An Integral Part of Global Innovation and Research Team.
- Developed the technical POCs for large scale data collection, Ingestion and Validation activities.

#### Technical Skills

Programming Languages Python   SQL	•	•	•	•	•
<b>Databases/DWH</b> MySQL   Oracle   Snowflake	•	•	•	•	
<b>Data Transformation Tools</b> Pyspark   Pandas   Polars   DB	• Γ	•	•	•	•
<b>DevOps Tools</b> Git   Bitbucket   Docker	•	•	•	•	
<b>Cloud Services</b> Databricks   Blob   ADF   S3	•	•	•	•	
<b>Project Tracking Tools</b> JIRA and Confluence	•	•	•	•	
Machine Learning Models Tree-based Models   Azure ML (StackEnsambler)	•	•	•	•	
<b>Data Visualization Tools</b> PowerBI   Tableau	•	•	•		

### 🗁 Projects Summary

# Cash Performance View (StanChart)

- Tech: Pyspark, Docker, GIT, JFROG

   Architected, Developed and Deployed Reporting Application to monitor the Bank's Cash Revenue (NFI and NII) and Liabilities for Corporate Clients.
- Automated data extraction from Bank's Internal Systems (Oracle BI and HDFS) using SQL, Pyspark and Shell Scripting.
- Transformed the Data using Python-Polars library to build cost effective data processing modules.
- Discovered the excel workbook level Encryption Method in Python to meet
- bank compliance.

   2000 Analytical Sales Level Reports are auto-sent to Bank Sales Executives and auto-shared the 42 Country Level Reports to Country Sales Leadership in sharepoint.

#### Stores Data Classification (NielsenIQ) Tech: Python, Imblearn, Polars, Pandas, Oracle SQL & Azure ML, Docker, Eliza (ML Ops),JFROG

- Acting Lead Developer to implement classifier for highly imbalanced binary classification problem.
- Developed and Automated Data Extractions from Oracle OLTP Datababse for 80 countries datasets.
- Performed EDA and explored various techniques to optimized the model performance.
- Built docker file and deployed the solution to Jfrog artifactory to enable CICD.

• Reduced total ~50% manual validation efforts(20 FTEs work) by deploying the models for 80 countries.

# Retailer Health Dashboard (NielsenIQ) Tech: Oracle SQL, ADF, Databricks(Pyspark), Azure-Blob & PowerBI

Used 2 different data sources (oracle database and remote on-prem storage) for data ingestion using Azure Data Factory.

Developed ,deployed & schedule rulebased transformation pipelines using Databricks - Pyspark.

Built store level and item level KPIs for Retailers FMCG Data.

The automated ETL data pipelines processes 20 million records weekly.

# Ecom Data Acquisition (NielsenIQ) Tech: Scrapy, Selenium, RapidFuzz, EasyOCR, Polars, Pandas, Azure Data Lake, Multiprocessing

- Lake, Multiprocessing
   Acted as Lead Developer for various mid to large scale webscraping Initiatives.
- Explored and Implemented various robust webscraping techniques like APIs, Sitemaps, Bypass Antibots, Optimal Usage of external proxy services.
- Designed and Developed various Web Scrapers to scrape product images, price, sales, units and categories data (Retailers and Google sites) to extract ~2 million products data every week.
- Developed and deployed various webscrapers for Italy based retailer websites in order to extract the weekly promotional flyers(Avg 20 GB Data Extraction).
- Built various shell script utilities to schedule the webscraper jobs.
  Automated end to end data ETL/EL
- Automated end to end data ETL/EL pipelines and stored the data in azure datalake.